Finding Aid for Kendall Wingrove papers, 1983-2005
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Kendall Wingrove papers 1983-2005, 1987-1999
Wingrove, Kendall.
7 linear feet
0798 Aa 2
Press official for Michigan House of Representatives Republican Policy Committee; reports of Committee Task Forces, press clippings, research materials, internal memorandum, and documents related to the career of Speaker Paul Hillegonds.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Kendall Wingrove (donor no. 9886 ) in 2007.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Kendall Wingrove worked as a press official for the Republican Party of Michigan in the last decades of the 20th Century, and the early 21st Century. He has served in various capacities: as Press Secretary in the Michigan House of Representatives, as Communications Specialist of the House Republican Communications Section, and as Director of the House Republican Communications Services. During the 1980s and 1990s, Wingrove handled the press affairs of the House Republican Policy Committee and amassed a large collection of materials relating to the Task Forces undertaken by the committee.
The documents contained in this collection focus primarily on the setting of policy agendas by the Michigan Republican Party in the State House of Representatives in the 1980s, 90s and 2000s. The record group has been divided into four series: House Republican Policy Committee Task Forces, Materials Compiled as Communications Specialist of the House Republican Communications Section, Materials Compiled as Director House Republican Communications Services and Miscellaneous.
Subjects:
Michigan. Legislature. House of Representatives. House Republican Policy Committee.; Republican Party (Mich.); Wingrove, Kendall.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-; Michigan--Politics and government--1981-1990.; Michigan--Politics and government--1991-2000.; Michigan--Politics and government--2001-2010.
- House Republican Policy Committee Task Forces
  The House Republican Policy Committee Task Forces series is broken down into a number of subseries organized chronologically by the years of the various task forces. These files, assembled throughout the history of the Policy Committee by press official Kendall Wingrove, consist mostly of news clippings about the various task forces assembled at different phases of the policy making process. Also included are a variety of press materials used in the research of a variety of policy initiatives, internal memoranda and press releases, and the draft and final reports submitted to the Michigan House of Representatives by the Task Forces.
  - 1986 Project '86 (Forerunner of Policy Committee) (Box 1)
  - 1987
    - Crime Reduction Task Force (Box 1)
    - Long Term Care Task Force (Box 1)
    - Property Tax/ School Finance Reform Task Force (Box 1)
    - Welfare Reform Task Force (Box 1)
  - 1988
    - AIDS Task Force (Box 1)
    - Child Care Task Force, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Farm Overseas Opportunity Development (F.O.O.D.) Task Force (Box 1)
    - Illegal Drugs Task Force, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Job Competitiveness Task Force (Box 1)
  - 1989
    - Child Care Challenge (Box 1)
      (see binder in box 4)
    - Children at Risk Task Force, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Drunk Driving Task Force (Box 1)
    - Educational Options That Work Task Force (Box 1)
    - Fiscal Future of Local Government Task Force (Box 1)
    - Natural Resources Management Task Force (Box 1)
    - Prison Initiatives Task Force (Box 1)
      (see also binder in box 4)
  - 1990
    - Accountability in State Government Task Force (Box 1)
    - Affordable Health Care Task Force (Box 1)
    - Child Care Challenge, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Environmental Cleanup Task Force (Box 1)
    - Taxpayer Rights Task Force, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1991
    - Affordable Housing Task Force (Box 1)
    - Campaign Finance Reform Task Force, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Child Care Challenge (Box 2)
  - 1992
    - Child Care Challenge (Box 2)
    - Privatization in State Government Task Force (Box 2)
    - Property Taxation Review Task Force (Box 2)
    - Recycling Task Force (Box 2)
    - Tourism Task Force, 2 folders (Box 2)
      (see also binder in box 5)
    - Urban Strategy and Community Development Task Force (Box 2)
  - 1993-1994
    - Agriculture Task Force (Box 2)
    - Land Use Planning Task Force (Box 2)
    - Higher Education Task Force (Box 2)
    - Port Development Task Force (Box 2)
    - Senior Policy Task Force (Box 2)
    - Youth Violence Task Force, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - 1995
    - A.W.A.R.E. Task Force (Box 2)
    - New Business and Entrepreneurial Development Task Force (Box 2)
    - Right-Sizing State Government Task Force (Box 2)
    - Traffic Safety Task Force, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Traffic Safety Task Force, 1 folders (Box 3)
  - 1996
    - Alternatives to Incarceration Task Force (Box 3)
    - Health Database Task Force (Box 3)
    - Higher Education Task Force (Box 3)
  - 1997
    - Safe Neighborhoods Alliance (Box 3)
    - Transportation Beyond the Year 2000 Task Force (Box 3)
  - 1998
    - Senior Citizens Task Force (Box 3)
  - 1999
    - Cultural Tourism and Heritage Task Force (Box 3)
    - Government Waste Task Force (Box 3)
    - Task Force Committee Chair Handbook (Box 3)
      (see binder in box 5)
  - 2000
    - Consumer Issues Task Force (Box 3)
  - Task Force Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Task Force records, in binders
    - 1989 Child Care Challenge (Box 4)
    - 1989 Prison Initiatives Task Force (Box 4)
    - 1990 Taxpayer Rights Task Force (Box 4)
    - 1991 Campaign Finance Reform Task Force (Box 4)
    - 1992 Tourism Task Force (Box 5)
    - 1995 Traffic Safety Task Force (Box 5)
    - 1999 Task Force Committee Chair Handbook (Box 5)
- Materials Compiled as Communications Specialist of the House Republican Communications Section
  The Materials Compiled as Communications Specialist of the House Republican Communications Section series consists of bound volumes of documents describing various policy programs initiated by the Michigan Republican Party during Kendall Wingrove's tenure as Communications Specialist.
  - 1996 House Democratic Casino Gaming Legislation (Box 5)
  - 1996 House Seatbelt Legislation (Box 5)
  - 1996 Michigan Kids Identity Sticker Program (Box 5)
- Materials Compiled as Director House Republican Communications Services
  The Materials Compiled as Director House Republican Communications Services series consists of bound volumes of documents describing various policy programs initiated by the Michigan Republican Party during Kendall Wingrove's tenure as Director of Communications Services.
  - 2001 Anti-Terrorism Measures (Box 6)
  - 2001 Bipartisan House Land-Use and Environment Committee (Box 6)
  - 2001 End-of-Life Care Reform (Box 6)
  - 2002 Learning Without Limits Campaign, 1 videotapes VHS (TM); 2 volumes (Box 7)
  - 2003 Intermediate School District Reform (Box 7)
  - 2003 Michigan Electoral Reform (Box 7)
- Miscellaneous
  The Miscellaneous series which concludes the collection is organized into three subseries. The General Press subseries consists of press releases, clippings, and other assorted materials relating to the Michigan Republican Party, collected by Kendall Wingrove during the 1980s. The Michigan House of Representatives subseries that follows is made up of documents that chronicle particular events or legislative initiatives that relate to the state house as a whole, and not simply the Republican Policy Committee. The final subseries of the collection, Speaker Paul C. Hillegonds's Press Files are materials assembled by Wingrove which focus specifically on the career of the state representative and Republican speaker of the state house.
  - General Press (Box 3)
  - 1983 Michigan Republican Party Press Releases, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - 1983-1990 Press Clippings (Box 3)
  - 1995-2000 House Democratic Task Force Materials (Box 3)
  - Michigan House of Representatives
    - 1992 Fiscal Agency Scandal Press Clippings (Box 3)
    - 1993 House Ethics Bill HB 4584, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - 1993 House Oversight Committee (Box 3)
    - 1993 Special Committee on Health Care Reform (Box 3)
  - Speaker Paul C. Hillegonds's Press Files
    - 1990 Financial Disclosure (Box 3)
    - 1993 Acceptance of Speaker's Position (Box 3)
    - 1996 Legislation (Box 3)
    - 1997 Detroit Renaissance Clippings (Box 3)